

Full-stack developer with expertise in AWS, application architecture design, DevOps and team management. Specialized in building web applications with React and Node.js that are written in TypeScript and deployed to Docker or Kubernetes environments using CI/CD pipelines.

Email

manuel.henke@yahoo.de

LinkedIn

<u>linkedin.com/in/manuel-henke</u>

Phone

+49 1517 0360 717

Website

henkebyte.com

Work Experience

facilioo

Nov 2024 - present

Senior Software Engineer

I lead the development of the customer app across web, Android, and iOS using Angular, TypeScript, C# (.NET Framework), and MariaDB. I manage DevOps, release management, and deployments with Docker, GitHub Actions, and AWS, while ensuring smooth internal and external communication. My role combines engineering, DevOps, and product strategy to drive innovation and deliver high-quality solutions.

GT-ARC (TU Berlin)

Jul 2023 - Oct 2024

Team Lead: Platform & Applications

Oct 2023 - Oct 2024

I was leading a small team of developers to build a data platform as distributed system for our automated vehicles and road infrastructure using Kafka, Postgres and Python. While participating in application development, I was the Tech Lead, Product Owner and responsible for the deployment to Kubernetes/Docker environments via GitLab pipelines that I introduced.

Researcher & Software Developer

Jul 2023 - Oct 2024

My research focused on Cooperative, Connected and Automated Mobility (CCAM) alongside the BeIntelli project. I was responsible for developing web applications to make automated driving tangible. These applications were built using TypeScript, React, Mapbox, MUI, Express.js, Socket.IO, and Prisma.

OEV Online Dienste

Dec 2019 - May 2023

Fullstack-Developer (Working Student)

- WordPress web application (PHP) with serverless backend functionality written in Java
- Alexa Skill with serverless backend services (JS)
- Multi-tenant Web Components library (TS)
- Corporate web application using TypeScript, React, Fastify, MongoDB, Keycloak, Kubernetes/Helm

VKB Jun 2018 - Nov 2019

Software Developer (Working Student)

- Developed a WordPress-based web shop using PHP
- · Built microservices in Java as backend
- Created the frontend with Bootstrap and jQuery

Education

Technical University of Berlin 2016 - 2023

M.Sc. - Information Systems Management (1.3) 2020 - 2023

Thesis: "Implementation of a use case mapper for CCAM based mobility solutions in the platform economy framework" (1.0)

B.Sc. - Information Systems Management (1.9) 2016 - 2020

Thesis: "Design and development of a cloud-based solution approach for automated home accessibility assessment as an iOS app" (1.0)

Languages

Invacariat/TypeCariat

German	English
Native	Proficient

Skills

JavaScript/TypeScript	•••••
React	•••••
HTML, CSS	•••••
Vue.js	••••
Angular	••••
Docker	••••
Java	••••
Swift	•••00
Kubernetes	•••00
SQL	•••00
Python	••000
PHP	••000

Interests

Cycling, Open-Source Development, Traveling